SANSAR CHAND SANKHYAN

DevOps Engineer

Contact

Address

New Delhi, DL, 110022

Phone

+91-9971545175

E-mail

sansarsankhyan2391@gmail. com

Skills

Linux

Amazon web services (AWS)

Kubernetes

Prometheus & Grafana

Jenkins

Helm

Ansible

Terraform

MysqIDB & PostgreSQL

Professional with 5+ years experience in DevOps. Flexible and versatile and able to work under pressure. Area's majorly worked on are AWS, AWS EKS, Kubernetes, Docker, ELK for Logging, Prometheus & Grafana

for monitoring, Terraform for AWS infra management and Jenkins CICD.

Work History

2019-09 -Current

DevOps Engineer

Monotype Solutions India Private Limited, Noida, Uttar Pradesh

- Managing Kubernetes cluster.
- Continues integration (Jenkins) and Continuous deployment. (Helm & spinnaker)
- Set Up and manage monitoring stack. (Prometheus and Grafana)
- Managing logging using ELK stack.
- Using Terraform to create/manage AWS Infra components.
- Set Up and manage RabbitMQ Cluster.
- Set Up Solution for RabbitMQ queue's messages-based pods autoscaling in Kubernetes.
- Used AWS spot instances as Kubernetes nodes for test/staging environments.
- Installation and deployment Web and App servers using Configuration management Ansible tool.
- AWS EFS storage incorporated in Kubernetes pods.
- Deploy code on authentication platform auth0 and logging integration with ELK.
- Created Jenkins pipelines to deploy node, python and php based applications.

2019-02 -2019-08

Associate DevOps Engineer

Prop Tiger Realty Pvt. Ltd, Gurgaon, Haryana

- Worked on AWS Infrastructure deployment and management using AWS services like EC2, S3, VPC, RDS (Relational database service), Auto scaling, Load balancers (ELB/ALB), IAM, CloudFront, Cloud watch, Trusted advisor, AWS billing management etc.
- Worked with various databases like MySQL and PSQL which includes making DML queries, Tuning

- parameters for better performance and DB backup/restore or table backups/restore.
- Having experience of DB migration from local to AWS RDS using AWS DMS (database migration service) with no/very minimal downtime.
- Deployment and management of Web and App Servers through Configuration management Ansible tool.
- Managing AWS EC2 instances using AWS spot fleet and using third party tool Spotinst for saving up to 75% of cost as compared to demand instances.
- Using JENKINS for Continuous Integration/Delivery of build and Deployment process.
- Worked on security aspects of instances and DB which includes security groups, rotating IAM keys and S3 bucket police's.
- Configured and management of ELK stack for logs shipping and using groks filters for log parsing/filtering over Logstash/Kibana.

2016-01 -2019-01

Technical Operations Engineer

"Mahindra Comviva" client on the payroll of Magna InfoTech Pvt Ltd, Gurgaon, Haryana

- Deploying software patches on production servers and working together with development team to debug and resolve issues during or post deployment.
- Written and deployed scripts like password expiry alerts mechanism for all production servers
- Written and deployed Monitoring scripts to check status of any application/process on a server and starts it if found stopped.
- Managing EC2 Instance (servers) on AWS cloud That includes volume addition, volume expansion, snapshot creation and making volume thereafter package installations)
- Configure and manage AWS infra components like VPC,LB and S3.
- Integration of Cisco CSR VPN on AWS cloud with Content Partner's cloud VPN like AWS VPN, Google cloud VPN and AZURE VPN.
- Working on MYSQL Databases which includes writing DML's and DB backup/restore etc.

Education

2012-06 -	Master of Technology: VLSI Design
2014-07	ITM University - Gurgaon, Haryana
2008-06 - 2012-03	Bachelor of Technology: Electronics And Communications Engineering
	Global Institute of Technology And Management - Gurgaon

Certifications

2018-04	AWS Certified Solutions Architect- Associate
2021-04	AWS Certified Solutions Architect- Professional